data.gov.uk 2019-04-24

# Privacy - data.gov.uk

Last updated 23 May 2018

##  Who we are 

Find open data is a data service provided by the [Government Digital Service](https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/government-digital-service) (GDS) which is part of the Cabinet Office. Our job is the digital transformation of government. 

Data.gov.uk helps people to find and use open government data, and supports government publishers to maintain data. 

The data controller for GDS is the Cabinet Office — a data controller determines how and why personal data is processed. For more information read the Cabinet Office’s entry in the [Data Protection Public Register](https://ico.org.uk/ESDWebPages/Entry/Z7414053). 

##  What data we need 

The personal data we collect from you will include: 

  * your name
  * your email address
  * your organisation

The legal basis for processing this data is in the exercise of a public task of a Government Department to undertake its functions. 

##  Why we need it 

We collect your personal data so we can provide access to the publishing service and to send you email notifications about service changes. 

We collect an email address and name so we can verify you work for the publishing organisation. 

##  What we do with it 

We use the data you provide to set up your account so you can manage and publish data. From time to time, we might need to update you about changes in the service. 

We will not:

  * sell or rent your data to third parties
  * share your data with third parties for marketing purposes

We will share your data if we are required to do so by law — for example, by court order, or to prevent fraud or other crime. 

##  How long we keep your data 

We will only retain your personal data for as long as it is required by law. In general, this means that we will only hold your personal data for the length of time you use this service, or up to 12 months after you leave the service whereby all information will then be deleted. 

##  Children’s privacy protection 

We understand the importance of protecting children’s privacy online. Our service is not designed for, or intentionally targeted at, children 13 years of age or younger. It is not our policy to intentionally collect or maintain data about anyone under the age of 13. 

##  Where your data is processed and stored 

To make sure that your data is as safe as possible, we design and maintain systems with secure accounts. Your personal data will not be transferred outside of the [European Economic Area (EEA)](https://www.gov.uk/eu-eea) while it’s processed at GDS. 

##  How we protect your data and keep it secure 

We are committed to doing all that we can to keep your data secure. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place technical and organisational procedures to secure the data we collect about you. 

For example, we protect your data using varying levels of encryption. We also make sure that any third parties that we deal with have an obligation to keep all personal data they process on our behalf secure. 

##  What are your rights 

You have the right to:

  * request information about how your personal data is processed and to request a copy of that personal data 
  * request that any inaccuracies in your personal data are rectified without delay 
  * request that any incomplete personal data is completed, including by means of a supplementary statement 
  * request that your personal data is erased if there is no longer a justification for it to be processed 
  * request that the processing of your personal data is restricted in certain circumstances — for example, where accuracy is contested 

If your personal data is processed on the basis of consent, you have the right to: 

  * request a copy of any personal data you have provided, and for this to be provided in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format 

##  Changes to this notice 

We may change this privacy notice at our discretion at any time. In that case the ‘Last updated’ date at the top of this page will also change. Any changes to this privacy notice will apply to you and your data immediately. If these changes affect how your personal data is processed, GDS will take reasonable steps to make sure you know. 

##  Questions and complaints 

The data controller for your personal data is the Cabinet Office. Contact the GDS Privacy Team if you have any questions or think that your personal data has been misused or mishandled. 

Email: [gds-privacy-office@digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk](mailto:gds-privacy-office@digital.cabinet-office.gov.uk)

The contact details for our Data Protection Officer are: 

The Data Protection Officer provides independent advice and monitoring of our use of personal information. 

If you have a complaint, you can also contact the [Information Commissioner](https://ico.org.uk/), who is an independent regulator set up to uphold information rights. 

Information Commissioner’s Office  
0303 123 1113  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF
